cincinnatistate.edu 2016-06-09

# Privacy Statement — Cincinnati State

Cincinnati State Technical and Community College does not collect personal information about visitors to our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. There is no requirement for you to provide any information at our website. If you do provide information, Cincinnati State does not sell, exchange, or release information gathered from your visit to our website to parties outside the college without your consent. Once we obtain your consent, we consider it valid until revoked by you.

### Information collection and storage

When you visit our website, we automatically gather and store the information outlined below so that we can track the use of our website in order to make improvements. This information is stored and used in aggregate only, and is not used to identify or contact you personally. Information gathered includes:

  * The IP address from which you access our Website
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account)
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our website
  * The date and time you access our site
  * The pages, files, documents, and links that you visit
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked to our website

Cincinnati State has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of cincinnatistate.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

### Cookies

In addition to information collected automatically, we may also collect cookies, which are small pieces of information sent to your browser by a website that you visit. Cookies are used to track usage patterns, traffic trends, and customer behavior, as well as to record other information from the website. When you register on the website, cookies also allow us to save information so that you will not have to re-enter it the next time you visit. Many content adjustments and customer service improvements are made based on the data derived from cookies. Information that we collect from cookies will not be used to create profiles of users and only will be used in aggregate form.

You may set your browser to refuse cookies from any website that you visit. If you so choose, you may still gain access to most of the college's website, but you may not be able to take advantage of some interactive elements offered.

### Personal information

The Cincinnati State website will only collect personal information which you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, sending emails; completing membership forms; registering for classes, events, or other programs; responding to surveys; or ordering merchandise. If you provide us with personal information, we will normally respond to your inquiry, request, or order. We may also contact you to provide information about college activities, programs, membership and development opportunities, and special events that may interest you.

Cincinnati State Technical and Community College will only share information about you to other parties when one or more of the following conditions apply:

  * We have your consent to share the information
  * We need to share your information to provide the service or product you requested
  * We need to send your information to companies who work on behalf of Cincinnati State Technical and Community College to provide a service or product to you
  * We need to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or any other legal process
  * We find it necessary to protect and defend the legal rights and/or property of Cincinnati State Technical and Community College.

Cincinnati State will not release any information other than directory information without a student or former student’s written consent. Directory information includes: name, address, college email address, telephone number, date and place of birth, major field of study, participation in Cincinnati State activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance at Cincinnati State, degrees, certificates and awards received, and the most recent previous educational institution attended. If you are a student or former student and do not want your directory information released, you must complete a form requesting it not be released and file the form with the Office of the Registrar.

### Linking

External links whose privacy practices we do not control are available throughout Cincinnati State’s website for your convenience. Once you leave Cincinnati State’s website via such a link, you are no longer subject to our privacy practices. Cincinnati State Technical and Community College is not responsible for the privacy practices nor the content of non-Cincinnati State websites, and such link is not intended to be an endorsement of the non-Cincinnati State website or its content.

### Changes

Cincinnati State Technical and Community College may need to change our privacy statement because of changes in the law, in technology, in Cincinnati State’s business, or in our attempts to serve your needs better. We will use every effort to communicate in a timely manner any changes to our privacy statement. From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically. We will use for these new purposes only data collected from the time of the policy change forward.

### Comments?

If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this website or if you have any comments or suggestions for our website, please contact us.
